# Curriculum Vitae BENIGNO CALVO ADIEGO

General Manager. International Executive with experience in Consumer Goods, Chemical and IT sectors. Leadership skills, creative and good communicator. Demonstrated experience in Sales, Operations and Development. Trained in Procter & Gamble, has widened his experience through startups and middle sized multinationals. Optimistic and hard worker with strong technical background. Values above all, the creation of lasting value through proper empowerment and development of the people in his working team.

# **Professional Experience:**

## Sep 2013 - Present

General Manager. Iberchem Tunisie. Iberchem Group. Based in Tunisia

**Iberchem Tunisie** produces and commercialises fragrances for home care, fabric care, personal care, cosmetics and fine fragrances, shipping to most northern African Countries (Maghreb) for its parent, Iberchem Group.

## Responsibilities:

- Establish Strategic Plan for the company.
- Overall responsibility for P&L.
- Direct management of Sales Team and local marketing efforts.
- Budgeting, staffing and leadership.
- Ensure day to day operations of the business.
- Reporting to Iberchem Group CEO

#### Main achievements:

- Bringing company processes and technology up to European standards.
- Handling strategic investment projects and managing a problematic human resources situation while keeping the costs down, throughout a political and economical crisis with high unions unrest.
- Annual sales growth of over 25% in 2015, doubling business since 2013, meeting and exceeding Corporate Strategic Plan for the last 3 years both in sales and EBITDA. Invoicing TND 10M, and managing 35 full time employees spanning R&D, Production, Logistics, Administration and Sales departments.

### Sep 2010 - Aug 2013

### Deputy General Manager. Iberchem Group. Based in Murcia

**Iberchem Group** is a private equity owned Spanish company with turnover in excess of €100M that produces and commercialises fragrances and flavours in more than 100 countries, with subsidiaries like Iberchem Tunisie in 11 countries across 5 continents.

# Responsibilities:

- Support executive director in the development and implementation of Iberchem's strategic plans and policies
- Responsibilities as Chief Information Officer for the group.
- Coordination and management of Sales and Marketing Teams.
- Implement and oversee company initiatives and projects.
- Reporting to Iberchem Group CEO

#### Main achievements:

- Developing and implementing a dynamic system for pricing and controlling salesmen thanks to which, the company was able to increase its EBITDA by more than 3 points.
- Implementing SAP CRM and Dashboard system of reporting.
- Integrating R&D processes and information across departments ensuring security, ease of use and workload control.

# Jan 2002 - Aug 2010

# Founder and General Manager. Alben Das. Based in Madrid

**Alben Das** provided complete IT department and infrastructure externalisation to medium sized companies, with solutions ranging from cloud computing to ERP implementations through service contracts rather than the traditional pay per project model.

Executed company startup, viability, planning and investor search. Responsible for all areas within the company:

sales, customer service, finance, legal, HHRR, local and international vendor management... building up the company from scratch up to circa €3M turnover with 15 employees, becoming one of SAP partners in Spain.

Leading Supply Chain and Production process restructuring for Medium sized industrial companies. SQL based ERP implementations as well as SAP R3, establishing IT support teams and training programs for clients in the following sectors: Fragrances, Chemicals, Packaging, Sanitation, Pharmacy and Cosmetics Research, Rubber, Hospitality, Leisure and Construction.

#### Jul 1999 - Dec 2001

# Senior Systems Manager. Procter & Gamble. Multiple Locations

EMEA Supply Chain systems architecture. Global Product Manager for SAP WM. Responsible for design, planning and execution of the Supply Chain technologies and processes following global business objectives. Achieving a turnkey installation for 9 plants and 10 Distribution Centres on a big bang project involving over 1000 users throughout Europe managing a team 10 experienced project managers.

#### Jan 1998 - Jun 1999

## IT Project Manager. Procter & Gamble. Multiple Locations

Design and implementation of IT solutions for plants and distribution centers, managing teams up to 10 people. Projects done: Manchester with a 90000 pallet business serving over 250 shipments/day, and Skelmersdale responsible for all the picking for all UK (around 200000 cases picked per day). Managed radio frequency solutions, web, Unix and automated warehousing.

#### Nov 1996 - Apr 1998

### IT Manager. Promofinarsa - Ibercaja. Zaragoza

In charge of the management and exploitation of IBERCAJA's Mainframe RDB databases for Direct Marketing and Promotions. Automation of Phone Direct Marketing with 30+ users reaching over 200.000 consumers per campaign.

### Other Achievements:

**2015** Tuniso-Spanish Chamber of Commerce: Founding Member and Vocal. Project preparation and presentation, networking with key figures in the Tunisian-Spanish commerce, as well as political figures needed to push the project through. Dealing with Office of Foreign Commerce as well as the different Embassies.

# **Education:**

1994 – 1995 Brussels Erasmus Université Libre de Bruxelles (ULB)

1990 – 1996 Zaragoza Master's, Postgraduate Degree Electrical & Electronic Engineering

Graduation "Cum Laude"

# Languages:

Spanish Mother tongue.

English Full professional proficiency.
French Full Professional proficiency.

Arabic MSA written and oral beginner. Better knowledge of Tunisian dialect.

## Other:

**IT Skills**: Project management experience in multiple ERP implementations, mostly SAP R3 but also Navision, Adonix, Aqua and Open ERP. Data mining and statistical programing with R Language.

**Interests:** *Music Composition* for piano, orchestral and music for the media as well as the occasional song with lyrics. *Self development* through continuous learning and *meditation*..

## **Personal Data:**

Nationality Spanish, October 04, 1972

Contact Data <u>benignoc@gmail.com</u> · (+216) 58 430 188 · (+34) 650 238 745.

Current Address 7 Omar ibn Raabia · La Marsa, 2071 · Tunisia